他们迟了
They're late.
布伦达 我们马上就到
Brenda, we're coming up behind.
拖住他们
Keep 'em busy.
坐稳
Hang on!
快报告
Call it in!
019号列车在行进中
Transport zero-one-niner,
遭遇袭击
we got trouble on the rail line.
23英里处 快来支援
Mile 23, send backup! Send backup!
收到 马上赶来
Roger that. On our way.
太疯狂了 托马斯
This is crazy, Thomas!
坐稳
Hang on.
再靠近一点
Get me closer!
上来 文斯
Come on, Vince!
文斯
Vince!
快跳
Jump!
该死
Shit!
我们走
Let's go!
看 飞行器
Hey! Berg!
019号列车 请注意
Zero-one-niner, be advised.
有可疑人物登上车尾
You've taken on boarders at the rear.
我们将发动进攻
We're engaging the truck now.
布伦达 有敌人来了
Hey, Brenda, you got company!
快 快 快
Go, go, go!
立即开火
Open fire.
小心
Watch out!
该死的
Holy shit!
托马斯 靠你自己了 坚持住
Thomas, you're on your own. Don't die.
祝你好运
Good luck!
我们该走了 快
We gotta move. Come on!
快 快 听到了没有
Go, go! You heard him!
把包给我
Give me the bag!
射击 小心 隐蔽
Shoot!
卧倒 卧倒
Get down! Get down!
文斯
Vince?
弄好了 快躲起来
We're set! Cover your ass!
前进 快 快
Go, go, go!
躲起来
Take cover!
前进 快走 快 快
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
后五节车厢被劫 赶快停车
We lost the rear five. Stop the train!
纽特
Newt!
好了 来吧 我们走 走了
All right, come on, let's go. Come on!
米诺
Minho!
米诺 听见吗
Minho, can you hear me?
这里 这里
This one. This one!
糟糕
Oh, shit!
很快就过来了
It's gonna be close.
来啊
Hello!
狡猾的小混蛋
Squirrelly bastard.
我们能行 能行
We got 'em! We got 'em!
马上下车 举起双手
Step out of the vehicle with your hands up.
我们走 各位
Let's go, boys.
停在那里 不要动
Stop right there. Don't move.
我说了不要动 混蛋
I said freeze, asshole!
都听你的 兄弟
Whatever you say, hermano.
快拦住他
Hold him back!
你可不要乱来
Y'all don't wanna do that now.
嘿 煎锅
Hey, Fry.
我们又见面了 快点 退后
Good to see you guys. Go on, back up.
嗨
Hi.
纽特 怎么样了
Newt, how you doing?
不要催我
Don't rush me.
见鬼
Shit!
纽特 快上来
Newt, get up here.
就快好了
Almost there.
纽特 快走
Newt, go!
- 他们哪儿去了 - 我不知道
- Where the hell are they? - I don't know!
走 他们人太多了
Go! There's too many of them!
好了 伙计们 我们来了
All right, boys, we're here!
继续前进
Keep moving!
- 快点 - 低点
- Come on! - Lower!
掩护我
Cover me!
快 好
Go, go!
好了 准备好了
All right, we're clear!
好 起飞了
Okay, we're going up.
文斯 赶快上来
Vince, get up here!
上来 文斯
Now, Vince!
- 太好了 - 哇
- Yeah! - Whoo!
我们就要回家了
We're going home, baby!
太好了
Yeah!
很好 伙计们 干得好 哇
All right, guys! Good job. Whoo!
好
Yeah!
《移动迷宫3：死亡解药》
阿里斯
Aris.
嘿
Hey,
你们没事吧
you guys okay?
嗯 没事
Yeah, we're fine.
天哪
Jesus.
没事就好 别怕
There you are. Oh, God!
你们没事了 好吗 先等会儿
It's okay. You guys are safe. All right? Just hang on.
我需要断线钳
I need the bolt cutters.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我没事 你怎么样
I'm fine. How are you?
他不在
He's not here.
我来帮你拿
I'll take one.
没事 你安全了
Come on down. You're safe here
医疗救助的往左边走
Need medical attention, move to your left.
我需要急救
I need first aid.
- 这边走 伙计们 - 赶紧下来
- Right this way, guys. - Come on down here.
大家都过来
Come on in, guys!
好的 伙计们 都过来
Okay, guys, over here!
行了 听好了
All right, listen up.
我知道你们受尽折磨
I know you've all been through hell.
我也很想说一切都过去了
I wish I could say our troubles are over.
但一切还没结束
But we're not through this yet.
实验部虎视眈眈 不肯放弃
WICKED's still out there. They're not giving up.
因为他们想利用你们
'Cause you got something they want.
他们抓你们是因为
They took you because you're immune
你们对一种能灭绝人类的病毒免疫
to a plague that's wiping out the human race.
他们认为应该牺牲你们研制解药
And they think you're worth sacrificing to find a cure.
可我反对
Well, I don't.
所以两天后
So in two days,
等我们把这艘船改造好
when we get this tub of rust seaworthy,
我们就离开这里
we're getting the hell outta here.
去一个实验部找不到你们的地方
We're gonna go to a place where WICKED will never find you.
在那里重新开始
A place you can start over.
重新有个家
A place you can call home.
我们离开这里
Are you with me?
快上船
Come on.
开始干活吧
Come on up here. Let's get to work.
快点 我需要帮手
Come on, I need some volunteers.
来吧
Let's go.
开始干活
Let's get to work.
把板条钉到船上
Let's get these crates on the boat.
我们两天后就出发
We got two days before we leave.
过来帮我个忙
All right. Give me a hand up here.
有什么事吗
May I help you?
看起来还行
It looks good.
感觉怎样
How you feeling?
好极了
Awesome.
就随便问问
I was just asking.
我知道 你就随便问问
I know, I know, you're just asking.
大家都是随便问问
Everybody's just asking.
别担心 如果被感染了
Don't worry. When I Crank out,
第一个告诉你 行吗
you'll be the first to know, okay?
给你 喝点吧
Here, drink this.
你们怎么这么久才来
Took you guys long enough to rescue us.
总算见到你了 伙计
It's good to see you, too, bud.
怎么回事
So what happened?
我反击了
I fought back.
至少试过了
Tried to, anyway.
能找到我们不容易
You're lucky you found us at all.
他们到处转移我们
They had us on the move a lot.
好像内部出了什么事
It felt like something big was happening.
知道他们要去哪儿吗
Any idea where they were heading?
我只知道
All I know is
他们老说一个城市
they kept talking about a city.
现在应该已经没有城市了吧
I didn't think there were any cities left.
是没什么城市了
That's because there aren't.
就算有也是废墟
Not still standing, anyway.
好了 等等 米诺在哪里
Okay, wait. What about Minho?
怎么不在火车上
Why wasn't he on the train?
抱歉 托马斯
I'm sorry, Thomas.
他之前在
He was.
他们带走了四五十个人
They got 40, maybe 50 kids.
具体数字还在统计
We're still compiling an official count,
飞行员看得很清楚
but the pilot got a good look.
应该是他们
He thinks it was them.
当然是他们
Of course it was them.
飞行器呢
What about the Berg?
我们追踪了几英里
We tracked it a few miles.
但他们拆了定位器
But someone must have known about the locator.
不见踪影了
They're totally off the grid.
快走 免疫者
Move it, Immunes.
C22
C22.
B9
B9.
我们还在搜索
We're searching the area,
但是 他们可能早就走了
but they're probably long gone by now.
不会 他们哪儿都不会去的
Oh, no, they're not going anywhere.
他还没救走最想救的人
He didn't get what he really wanted.
这里 就这里
There, that's it.
大概几百英里远
It's a few hundred miles.
根据火车线路和阿里斯的情报
Based on the railways, everything that Aris told us,
他们肯定要去这里
that's gotta be where they're headed.
带米诺去这里
That's where they're taking Minho.
我们带上所有人
We take everyone who can fight.
沿路追踪下去
Follow the roads where we can.
一周内就能回来
We can make it back within a week.
一周
A week?
我们花了六个月才到这里
It took us six months to get here.
现在我们已经有100多人了
We got over 100 kids here now.
我们不能一直留在返里
We can't just hang out here forever
毕竟闹出了大动静
after what we just pulled.
你在地图上随便找个地方就要去
You wanna wander off to some random point on the map.
都不知道那里的情况
You don't even know what's there.
我知道
I do.
那是几年前了
It's been a few years,
但我去过
but I've been there.
最后的城市
The Last City.
实验部这么叫它
That's what WICKED called it.
那里是他们的大本营
It was their whole base of operations.
如果那座城市还在
If that city is still standing,
你最好离它远点 伙计
that's the last place you wanna go, hermano.
那就是个狼窝
That's the lion's den.
我们什么没闯过
It's nothing we haven't done before.
对 但需要周密的计划
Yeah, with months of planning,
准确可靠的情报 和隐密的行动
and reliable information, the element of surprise,
可现在什么都没有
none of which we have now.
文斯 我想好了
Vince, I've thought this through.
你能听我说吗
Would you just hear me out?
上次我们没准备好就行动
The last time we went off half-cocked…
我失去了一切
I lost everything.
你还记得吗
You remember that?
我知道要救米诺 好吗
Look, I know it's Minho. All right?
但我不能不顾这些孩子的安危
But you can't ask me to put those kids
去救他一个
on the line for one man.
我做不到
I won't do it.
搜索该区域
Searching the grid now.
A区完毕
A is completed.
开始搜索B区
Scanning B-sector now.
糟了 快关灯
Shit. Hit the lights.
快走 快走
Let's go, let's go!
天哪 他们找过来了
Jeez, they're getting close.
说对了
You're right.
不能留在这
We can't stay here.
你这是要去哪儿
Where do you think you're going then?
纽特
Newt…
你别多说了
Don't be a twat about it.
我也一起
I'm already in.
走吧
Come on.
不 这次不行
No. No, not this time.
听着
Look,
就算我们找到米诺
even if we find Minho,
也未必能安全地逃出来
there's no guarantee we make it back from this.
那你就更需要帮手了 不是吗
Well, you'll need all the help you can get then, won't you?
我们一起死里逃生
Well, we started this together.
现在也要一起去救他
May as well end it that way, too.
好吧
Okay.
一起去救他
Let's go get him back.
不
No.
嘿
Hey!
嘿 不 不 等等 嘿
Hey! No, no, no. Wait. Hey!
等等 等等 没事的
Hey, wait, wait! Hey, it's okay! Hey!
他情况怎样
How's he doing?
呼吸状况还不错
Breathing levels look strong.
见鬼
Oh, shit!
不 不
No! No!
虽然效果不如迷宫
It's not as effective as the maze,
但似乎也有作用
but it seems to be working.
那就好
It's promising.
但我们还需要更多的人
But we'll need a larger sample to work with.
明白了
All right.
继续
Carry on.
不 不
No! No!
（前方两英里）
（强制感染筛查）
（感染症状）
你想让我进那里
You want us to go in there?
不是我想吓大家
I don't wanna come across as too negative,
但这里可狂客最喜欢出没的地方一
but if I was a Crank, that's exactly where I would be.
但我们现在别无选择
I don't think we have much of a choice.
那走吧 我坐副驾
All right. I get shotgun.
我们进来了
Well, here we go.
好 小心开慢点
Yeah, just take it nice and slow.
没事 只有一个
It's okay. It's just one,
那就慢慢开绕过他
so take it slow, go around him.
不要紧的
We'll be fine.
慢慢开
Take it slow.
求求你
Please.
帮帮我
Help me.
求求你
Please.
求你了 让我进去
Please! Let me in.
- 好了 煎锅 继续开 - 求你了 开门
- Okay. Fry, we gotta go. - Please! Open the door.
- 我们快点离开这里 - 为什么你不开门
- You need to go right now! - Why won't you open it?
快踩油门 煎锅
Just floor it, Fry!
- 坐稳了 - 加速 快
- Hold on! - Floor it! Come on!
- 快点 煎锅 甩掉他 - 我在甩
- Come on, Fry, shake him! - I'm trying!
快
Go.
坐稳了
Hang on!
天哪
Oh, God.
煎锅 小心
Frypan, watch out!
都没事吧 我没事
Everyone okay?
我的手
My hand.
煎锅 闭上眼睛
Fry, cover your eyes.
见鬼 你没事吧
Oh, shit. You okay, man?
- 没事 你呢 - 见鬼 我的手
- Yeah. You all right? - Shit, my hand.
等等 托马斯
Wait! Thomas!
托马斯 车门
Thomas, the door!
你能出来吗
Can you get out?
见鬼
Oh, shit. All right.
- 好了 能出来吗 - 煎锅 去那边
- Newt, you all right? - Fry, go around.
我在想办法出来
I'm trying to get out.
纽特 没事吧
Newt, you okay?
没事 我没事
Yeah, I think so.
煎锅 没事吧
Fry, you good?
见鬼
Oh, shit.
煎锅 我们得赶紧走
Frypan, I think we gotta move.
- 快 - 等一会
- Now! - Wait a minute!
- 快点 - 煎锅 快
- Right now! - Fry, now!
你在干什么 赶紧走 快啊
Come on, what are you doing? We gotta move! Come on!
- 快走 - 等等
- Come on! - Hold on!
- 煎锅 快走 快啊 - 等等
- Frypan gotta go! Come on! - Wait!
快点
Come on!
- 打得好 煎锅 - 谢谢
- Nice shot, Fry. - Thanks.
好了 我们快走
Okay. We gotta go.
走 走
Go, go!
煎锅 快啊 快走
Fry, come on, let's go!
- 煎锅 我们走 快走 - 快 快 快
- Fry, let's move, let's go! - Go! Go! Go!
小心
Watch out.
- 煎锅 能搞定吗 - 能
- Fry, you got any left? - Yeah!
好的 这边 这边
Okay. This way, this way!
行了 另一边 另一边
Okay, Fry. Other way, other way!
没子弹了
I'm out!
见鬼
Shit!
快进来
Hey, get in!
- 快 豪尔赫 快 - 快
- Go, Jorge, go! - Go!
挺住
Hang on!
真不简单
I'm impressed!
你们撑了差不多一整天
You guys almost lasted a whole day.
- 没事吧 - 没事
- You good? - Yeah.
抱歉 连累你们也跟着冒险
I'm sorry. I didn't wanna bring you guys into this.
我觉得他想说
I think what he's trying to say
谢谢你救了我们
is thanks for saving us.
不用客气
You're welcome.
嘿 别高兴太早
Hey, don't get your hopes up.
那边的关卡
That checkpoint back there,
是这座城最后的防线
that was the city's last defense.
如果它被突破 这座城将在劫难逃
If that was overrun, chances are the city is, too.
对 除非他们想到
Yeah, unless they figured out
别的办法阻止狂客
some other way to keep the Cranks out.
有意思
Funny…
我们被关了三年
Spent three years trapped behind walls,
拼命逃了出来
trying to break out,
现在却又要冲回去
and now we wanna break back in.
是啊 太讽刺了
Yeah. It's hilarious.
豪尔赫 我们怎么进去
Jorge, how do we get in?
别问我 兄弟
Don't look at me, hermano.
那些墙是新建的
Those walls are new.
我猜实验部最会这一招了
I guess that's WICKED's answer for everything.
站在这可没法弄清楚
Well, we ain't gonna figure it out from up here.
出发吧
Let's go!
你真的觉得他在那
You really think he's in there?
去了就知道
I guess we'll find out.
我想特瑞莎也在那里
You know she's gonna be there, too.
必须确保有足够的资源
We just have to make sure we have the resources.
我再联系你 很抱歉
And I'll keep in touch. Excuse me.
准备好了
Are you ready?
没事的
It'll be fine.
大家已经开始丧失信新
People are beginning to lose faith, Doctor.
告诉我们那只是个
When you sealed off the walls, you assured us
临时预防措施
that it would only be a temporary precaution.
为什么现在还没有解禁
Why have you now denied all entry?
因为状况有变 情况恶化了
Because things are changing. And not for the better.
感染率上升了百分之三百
Infection rates were up 300%.
幸运的是
Fortunately,
我们就要技术突破了
we may be on the verge of a breakthrough.
这就是A7号实验体
This is Subject A7.
他之前在迷宫里待了三年多
He spent over three years in the Maze Trials.
而且他体内产生的抗体
The antibodies produced in response
是我们见过最强的
have been the strongest we've ever seen.
我们正在提取一种新型血清
We're extracting a new serum as we speak.
如果你们同意少
And with your support,
我们就可以展开人体实验
we'd like to begin human trials.
谢谢你 博士 你想得非常好
Thank you, Doctor. That is very impressive.
但我们已经试过这种方法
But we have been down this road before.
坦白的说 我们都开始怀疑我们的
Frankly, we are all beginning to wonder if…
我们的资源是否应该用于别的地方
If our resources couldn't be better spent elsewhere.
- 你是说 - 建安全区
- Meaning? - Safe zones.
建和这一样的保护区
Protected areas like the one we're in.
这样我们能救更多的人
We could save as many people as possible.
更多的人吗
How many?
一千个
A thousand?
两千个
Two thousand?
你能保证新建的安全区就一定安全吗
And that's assuming your protected areas stay protected,
你知道这不可能
which we know they won't.
被感染的人数已经是健康人数的三倍
The infected already outnumber the healthy three-to-one.
安全区只能延缓死亡的到来
All you'd be doing is delaying the inevitable.
你们就没有人因病毒感染而亡吗
Have any of you ever lost someone to the virus?
我侄女
A niece.
安娜
Anna.
很抱歉没能帮到她
I'm sorry we weren't able to help her.
但试想如果我们能战胜这种病毒
But imagine if we were able to live with the virus.
活了下来
To survive it.
你就可以告诉安娜
Imagine being able to tell Anna
你能让她过上正常的生活
that you could give her the chance to live a normal life.
我们就要找到解药了
We've never been this close to a cure.
我们牺牲了太多才到这一步
And we've sacrificed a lot to get this far.
请不要
Please,
让这些牺牲付诸东流
don't let those sacrifices be for nothing.
做得不错
Nicely done.
他们不好说话 你表现得非常好
They can be a tough crowd. You handled them perfectly.
延缓死亡的到来
"Delaying the inevitable."
托马斯以前经常这样说我们
Thomas used to say the same about us.
你还经常想他吗
Do you still think about him?
我可以帮助你删除记忆
I can help you with that, those memories.
没必要揪着过去不放
There's no reason to keep holding on to them.
删掉就行了
It's a simple procedure.
我不想删掉
There is a reason.
我想记住
I want to remember.
找到解药
If we find a cure,
所有的付出才都值得
that's the only way all this was worth it.
但愿你是对的
I hope you're right.
这里破坏得很严重
This place has really gone through hell.
我们不要走散了
We just gotta stay together.
我们是那些无声者的代言人
We are the voiceof the voiceless!
而他们藏在高墙之内
They hide behind their walls,
还幻想着可以独占解药
thinking they can keep the cure for themselves,
然后看着其他人慢慢地死亡 腐烂
while they watch the rest of us wither and rot!
但我们的人数
But there are more of us
比他们多得多
than there are of them.
我提议
And I say,
大家站起来
we rise up
拿回属于我们的东西
and take back what is ours!
让我们一起 夺取胜利吧
Let's bring back a victory!
去叫詹森
Get Janson.
让我们进去
Let us in!
就是那儿 从那儿进去气
That's it. That's our way in.
让我们进去
Let us in!
去墙边
To the wall!
让我们进去 让我们进去
Let us in! Let us in! Let us in!
托马斯
Thomas!
应该不是这个地方
This is not what you're looking for.
这么多人拼命想进去
All these people trying to find their way in,
你觉得你能有新发现吗
you think you're gonna find something they can't?
走了这么远 我不想现在回头
Came this far. I'm not turning back now.
我们怎么卷进了这种事
What the hell did we get ourselves into?
快点走啊 给我让开
Get out of my way! Get out of my way!
托马斯 我感觉不太对
Thomas, this doesn't feel right.
你说对了 先生
You were right, sir.
无人机刚刚在墙外发现了他
The drone sweep picked him up outside the walls.
准备开始行动
Get the guns online.
各位 我们得走了 快看
Hey, guys, we gotta go now. Look.
快走 我们走
Let's go, let's go!
- 托马斯 我们走 - 我们离开这
- Thomas, let's go. - We gotta get out of here!
快啊 我们走
Let's go! Let's go!
快走 走 走 快 快
Go! Go! Go! Come on! Come on!
快离开这
Go! Keep going!
快点
Come on!
快跑
Move!
快跑 躲起来 进来
Come on! Get in! Get in!
快点 他们来了 快
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
快点
Come on!
- 跑这边 - 快点
- No way out! - Come on!
纽特 纽特
Newt! Newt!
把手给我拿开
Get your hands off of me!
不 布伦达
No! Brenda!
布伦达 布伦达
Brenda! Brenda!
快 快
Go, go, go!
放开我 放开我
Get off me! Get off me!
派人出去找
Send out a patrol.
找不到那小子就不要回来
Tell them not to come back until he's found.
进去
Let's go!
都出来
Get out!
你想丢哪儿
Where you going?
她在哪儿 你个混蛋
Where is she, you son of a bitch?
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey! Hey!
见鬼 住手 住手
Shit! Hey! Wait!
住手 住手 住手
Come on, come on, come on.
我在这 我在这
I'm right here. I'm right here!
- 好了 好了 - 行了
- Okay, okay, okay. - All right. Okay.
我在这 我在这
I'm right here. I'm right here!
布伦达
Oh, Brenda.
你们别紧张
Everybody relax.
我们是同一战线的
We're all on the same side here.
什么同一战线的 你到底是谁
What do you mean same side? Who the hell are you?
嘿 菜鸟
Hey, Greenie.
盖里
Gally?
不可能
No way.
不 等等
No, wait!
住手
Hold!
住手 没事的
Stop! It's all right!
行了 住手 别打了
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Stop! Stop it!
住手
Stop.
- 他杀了查克 - 对 我懂
- He killed Chuck. - Yeah, I know.
我记得 我也在场 好吗
I remember. I was there too, all right?
他当时被怪物咬了
But I also remember that he was stung
神志不清
and half out of his mind.
先冷静下来 好吗
Just calm down. All right?
拜托
Come on.
就猜到会这样
Kind of had that coming.
还有谁 煎锅 纽特
Anybody else? Fry? Newt?
你认识这个人
Do you know this guy?
老相识了
He was an old friend.
怎么会
How?
这怎么可能
How is this possible?
我们看到你死了
We watched you die.
不 你们丢下我等死
No, you left me to die.
如果我们刚才没找到你们
And if we hadn't found you when we did,
你们早就死了
you'd be dead right now.
你们来这千什么
What the hell are you doing here?
米诺
Minho.
实验室抓了他
WICKED has him here.
我们得想办法进去
We're looking for a way in.
我可以帮忙
I can help with that.
跟我来
Follow me.
我不会跟你去任何地方
I'm not going anywhere with you.
随你的便吧
Suit yourself.
但我能带你们进去
But I can get you through those walls.
离开迷宫后 我被一群
After the maze, I got picked up by a group
前往城市的人救了
headed to the city.
他们发现我是免疫者
They realized I was immune, patched me up,
就带我来这 交给了劳伦斯
and they brought me here to Lawrence.
城市被实验部控制后
This group's been at war with WICKED
这个组织就在和他们抗争
ever since they took control of the city.
实验部不可能永远躲在墙后
But WICKED can't hide behind those walls forever.
总有一天 他们会付出代价的
Day's gonna come, and they're gonna pay for what they've done.
听好
Listen, uh,
他平时很少见外人
he doesn't get a lot of visitors.
所以 我来和他说 好吗
So, let me do the talking. All right?
别盯着他看
And try not to stare.
玫瑰香气如此甜蜜
Rose took my nose, I suppose.
甜蜜 甜蜜 玫瑰香气
Suppose, suppose, took my nose…
如此甜蜜
I suppose.
盖里
Gally,
你安全回来就好
glad to see you made it back.
贾斯拍都告诉我了
Jasper told me what happened.
那就是屠杀
It was a slaughter.
我们抵挡不了重型武器
There's nothing we could do against those guns.
对
No,
他们既然胆敢捅马蜂窝
but they can only poke the hornet's nest so long
就等着被蛰吧
before they get stung.
这些人是谁
Now, who are these people?
为什么来这
Why are they here?
我们要进实验部
We need to get into WICKED.
盖里说你能帮我们进去
Gally said you can get us through the walls.
盖里该学着不要许下
Gally should know better than to make promises
兑现不了的承诺
that he can't keep.
再说了 高墙不过是第一个麻烦
Besides, that wall is only half your problem.
混入实验部基本不可能
Getting inside WICKED is impossible.
有个办法能试试
There might be a way now.
但是没有托马斯就做不到
But it doesn't work without Thomas.
是这样吗
Is that so?
知道我是谁吗
Do you know what I am…
托马斯
Thomas?
我是一个生意人
I am a businessman.
所以我绝不会去冒 不必要的风险
Which means that I don't take unnecessary risks.
我为什么要相信你
Why should I trust you?
因为我能帮你
'Cause I can help you.
如果你帮我穿过高墙
You see, if you can get me through those walls…
我就给你想要的
I can get you what you need.
你觉得我想要的是什么
What is it that you think I need?
时间
Time.
每分每秒
Every last drop.
这就是我想要的吗
Is that what I need?
实验部有我们想要的
WICKED has something we both want.
那这样吧
I'll tell you what.
你们进去两个人
Two can go for now.
其他人和我待在这
The rest stay down here with me.
只是为了确保 你会老老实实地回来
Just a little insurance to make sure you find your way back.
成交吗
We have a deal?
盖里 给他带路
Gally, show him the way.
小心点 托马斯
Be careful, Thomas.
盖里 照顾好他们俩
Gally, take care of these two.
好
Yeah.
太恶心了
This is gross.
天哪
Jesus.
是啊 太棒了
Yeah, this is great.
跟着我 还要走很远
Stay with me. We got a ways to go.
准备好
We're ready.
夏安
Shai?
特瑞莎女士
Hi, Miss Teresa.
嘿
Hi.
Hey.
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
还好
Okay.
这会让我好起来吗
Is that gonna make me better?
我希望会
I hope so.
还记得你给我讲的那个故事吗
Do you remember the story you were telling me?
你从小住的房子
About the house you grew up in?
我 不 不记得了
I don't remember.
湖边的那个
The one by the lake?
好烫啊
It burns.
别怕 别怕
I know, I know.
打完了 没事了
There we go. All done.
你真勇敢
You're so brave.
真是不可思议
Oh, that is incredible.
最快什么时候能给感染者注射
How soon can you administer to the infected?
你还挺有同情心
You show a lot of compassion
作为向人群开枪的凶手
for someone who just opened fire on a crowd.
你要我履行职责 有机会自然要动手
You told me to do my job. I had a shot. I took it.
但失手了 很明显
And missed, apparently.
巡逻队没有发现尸体
The patrols never found a body.
托马斯没被抓
Thomas is still out there.
那特瑞莎呢
What about her?
她知道吗
Does she know?
不
No.
别告诉她
She can't.
我需要她集中精力
I need her to stay focused.
马上提升全市的安全级别
Elevate security levels throughout the city.
我需要你处理好这一切 詹森
I'm counting on you to handle this, Janson.
红区
Red zone,
列车五分钟后驶离车站
departing the station in five minutes.
谢谢
Thank you.
这离迷宫中心远着呢
This is a long way from the Glade.
十五分钟后开始强制宵禁
Fifteen minutes to mandatory curfew.
请大家遵守秩序返回家中
Please proceed home in an orderly fashion.
注意这是为了你的安全
Remember, this is for your safety.
感谢您的配合
Thank you for your compliance.
我们最好快离开街道
Yeah, we better get off these streets.
我知道很难 但是你们要假装有经验
And I know it's hard, but act like you've seen it before.
警戒加强不少
They've definitely upped security.
我看应该跟你们有关系吧
I'm guessing you shanks have something to do with that.
好了 我们先走
All right, let's get outta here.
行了 纽特 你先上
All right, Newt, you're up.
我自己来
I got it.
就是这
There it is.
他们抓了米诺
If WICKED's got Minho,
肯定关在这
that's where they'll be keeping him.
劳伦斯一直在想办法溜进去
Lawrence has been trying to find a way in for years.
但这里到处都是卫兵
Place is crawling with soldiers.
哪儿都有摄像头
They got surveillance everywhere.
每层都有扫描仪
Scanners on every floor.
感觉就像个堡垒
Sounds like a bloody fortress.
你说有办法进去的
Yeah, I thought you said you had a way in.
应该有
I might.
You might?
什么叫应该有
What the hell do you mean "might"?
看看吧
Take a look.
我是说有办法
I said I had a way in.
可没说你会喜欢
I didn't say you were gonna like it.
不 肯定有别的办法
No. There's gotta be another way.
什么办法 你看过那栋楼
Like what? You've seen the building.
她是我们唯一的办法
She is our only way in.
你觉得她会帮我们
You really think she's gonna help us?
我又没说要去请她帮忙
I don't plan on asking for her permission.
是我听错了吗
Am I missing something here?
你们说的那个女的背叛过我们 对吧
This is the same girl who betrayed us, correct?
那个贱人
Same dick?
我喜欢她
I like her.
你怎么回事
What's going on?
怎么 怕你女朋友会受伤吗
What, are you afraid your little girlfriend's gonna get hurt?
你果然不仅仅是为了救米诺
Because this has obviously never been just about rescuing Minho.
对吧
Has it?
纽特 你在说什么
Wait, what are you talking about?
特瑞莎
Teresa.
要不是因为她
She's the only reason
米诺一开始也不会失踪
that Minho's even missing in the first place.
现在终于有机会救他了
Now we finally have an opportunity to get him back.
结果呢 你又不愿意了
And what? You don't want to because of her?
因为你心里
Because deep down inside
还在乎她 对不对
you still care about her, don't you?
你承认吧
Just admit it.
- 纽特 我 - 不要对我撒谎
- Newt, I… - Don't lie to me!
不要对我撒谎
Don't lie to me!
抱歉
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
刚才的事 很抱歉
Sorry about that. Back there.
看样子我是瞒不住了
I guess I can't hide this anymore.
为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
告诉你又有什么用呢
Didn't think it would make any difference.
我只知道实验部
All I know is that WICKED must have put me
把我关进迷宫是有原因的
in that maze for a reason.
也许他们只想知道你这样的免疫者
Maybe it was literally just so they could tell the difference
和我这样的普通人之间的区别
between immunes like you and people like me.
你知道的我们还有希望 纽特
You know we can still fix this, Newt.
放弃 好吗
Okay? We can.
不要担心我 要紧的是米诺
Don't worry about me. This is about Minho.
他现在需要我们
Now he needs us.
所以就算只有万分之一的机会
So if there is even the slightest chance
能救他出来
that we can save him,
只要有一点希望我们都要试一试
we can get him out of there, then we have to take that.
不管代价是什么
No matter what the cost.
好 我明白了
Okay. I hear you.
抬他起来
Let's get him up.
米诺
Minho.
能听见吗
Can you hear me?
这里有个小女孩
There's a little girl here.
她名叫夏安
Her name is Shai Lun.
她已经被感染了三个星期了
She's been infected for three weeks now.
但是米诺
But, Minho,
你能救她的命
you're going to save her.
而且你还能救很多的命
And you can save so many others.
我们在这付出的努力
Everything we're doing here,
没有白费
it's working.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
所以我们的工作非常重要
That's why this is so important.
我只想让你知道
I just wanted you to know.
特瑞莎
Teresa.
米诺
Minho?
你这个叛徒
You're a traitor!
我们那么信你
We trusted you!
- 滚开 - 放开她
- Get off! - Hey, let her go!
放开我 放开我
Get off me! Get off me!
我要杀了你 你这个叛徒
I'll kill you! You traitor!
你把他们都害死了
You killed them all!
好像很着急
Teresa, they need you in the med lab.
注意
It sounds serious.
我很遗憾 特瑞莎
I'm sorry, Teresa.
这不是你自句错
It's not your fault.
你真的已经尽力下
You did everything you could.
请大家注意 宵禁已经开始
This is an alert. Curfew is now in effect.
违反宵禁令外出者
Anyone caught in violation of curfew
将被立即驱逐出城
will be subject to immediate deportation.
托马斯
Thomas?
Thomas.
特瑞莎
Hey, Teresa.
你不应该来的
You shouldn't be here.
如果詹森发现你在这
If Janson finds out you're here…
我不会久留
I'm not staying.
我只是
It's just, uh…
我想见你
I had to see you.
我想问你个问题
I have to ask you something.
你后悔吗
Do you regret it?
背叛了我们
What you did to us?
有时候会
Sometimes.
但我做了我认为对的事
But I did what I thought was right.
这是我的选择
I'd do it again.
很好
Good.
难得放松一下是吗
Taking the edge off, I see.
很漂亮 是吧
Beautiful, isn't it?
是啊
Yes.
- 多漂亮的城市 - 嗯
- It's a lovely city. - Hmm.
那些墙
The walls.
当人们命悬一线时
It's amazing what people can accomplish
总会爆发非凡的力量
when their survival's at stake.
他们就没什么做不到的
Squeeze them hard enough, there's nothing they can't do.
没什么底线不能打破
No line they won't cross.
这只是一个小挫折
You've had a bit of a setback.
我们早就习惯挫折了
It's nothing we're not used to.
这次不一样
Not this time.
病毒通过空气已经传到城里了
The virus is airborne. It's inside the walls.
那个血清是最后的希望
That serum was our last chance.
最多一个月之内 所有人都会被感染
Anyone not already infected will be inside of a month.
好吧 我们还有办法
Okay. We can handle this.
只需要撤离关键人员
We just need to evacuate essential personnel,
然后继续北上再建立一个安全区
set up at another safe zone farther north.
这栋楼里还有二十八名免疫者
We've still got 28 immunes right inside this building.
我们还能找到更多
We can find more.
我相信
You would.
你会抓住每一个免疫者
You'd hunt every last one of them down
直到一个也不剩
till there was no one left.
尽管我们这样残忍地利用他们
In spite of everything we've done to them,
让他们受尽了折磨
everything we've put them through.
但至少我们给了他们生存的希望
At least we gave them the tools they'll need to survive.
也许他们能做到我们做不到的
Maybe they'll succeed where we've failed.
你这是告诉我你要放弃吗
Are you really telling me that you're giving up?
付出了那么多
After everything?
我不是要放弃 詹森
It's not about giving up, Janson.
是要做好失败的心理准备
It's about knowing when you've lost.
盖里
Gally?
接下来我们这样办
Here's how this is gonna go.
我们要问你几个问题
We're gonna ask you some questions,
你要老老实实地告诉我们答案
and you're gonna tell us exactly what we need to know.
从简单的开始 米诺在哪儿
We'll start off simple. Where's Minho?
听着 你们不会真的以为
You guys don't seriously think…
不要看他
Don't look at him.
为什么要看他
Why are you looking at him?
看着我
Look at me.
他不会帮你的
He's not gonna help you.
我们知道你们抓了米诺
Now, we know you have Minho in the building.
在哪儿
Where?
他和其他人都在关押区
He's with the others in holding.
地下三层
Sublevel three.
其他人有多少
How many others?
二十八个
28.
可以全部救出去
I can make that work.
不 你们不明白
No. No, you guys don't understand.
整层楼都严禁进入
The whole level's restricted.
你们没有指纹认证根本进不去
You can't get in without a thumbprint ID.
所以你要和我们一起去
That's why you're gonna come with us.
那可不一定
Well, I don't know.
我们也不一定需要她
We don't necessarily need her.
对吧
Right?
不用整个人
Not all of her.
- 有指纹就够了 - 盖里 你让开
- We just need her finger. - Gally, back off.
什么 你觉得过分了？
What, are you squeamish?
她对米诺做的事肯定更过分
I guarantee you she's done a lot worse to Minho.
不要那样做 你让开
That's not the plan. Back off.
没有任何区别 你们想怎么样都行
It won't make a difference. Do whatever you want to me.
但你们连门都进不去
You still won't get through the front door.
感应器会发现你们
The sensors will pick you up the…
因为我们 被标记了
We know. We're tagged.
实验部财产
Property of WICKED.
你也可以帮到我们
You're gonna help us with that, too.
放轻松点 可能有点疼
Try to relax. This is gonna sting.
你快点动手吧
Let's just get it over with.
她很享受吧
She enjoyed that.
也许你说得对
You're probably right.
拿着 看合不合适
Here. See if these fit.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢 纽特
- Thanks. - Thanks, Newt.
该出发了 老头子
Better get going, old man.
路可远着呢
Long road ahead of you.
你确定不听我的劝吗
You sure I can't talk you out of this?
这是最后的机会
It's your last chance.
知道吗 我不像你总是逃避战斗
You know, it's not like you to shy away from a fight.
寻找战斗也不是你的风格
And it's not like you to go looking for one.
我只是忍不住想 一旦我走出门
I just can't help but think if I walk out that door…
可能就见不到你了
I'm never gonna see you again.
我们从什么时候开始 为陌生人出生入死了
Since when do we go sticking our necks out for strangers?
我们以前也是陌生人
I was a stranger once, too.
- 不要让我们一直等你 - 不
- Just don't leave us hanging. - No.
不会的
Never.
她看起来很好 很健康
She's looking good healthy.
你们给她注射血清了
How've you been getting her serum?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
布伦达
Brenda.
没想到她还活着
I didn't think she'd still be alive.
上次什么时候治疗的
When was her last treatment?
在干将组织
At the Right Arm.
上次见你的时候
The last time we saw you.
那都好几个月了
But that was months ago.
托马斯 这根本不可能
Thomas, that's not possible.
她应该已经发作了
She should have turned by now.
根本不可能这么正常
There's no way she could possibly still…
好了 别说了
All right, that's enough.
你不相信我吗
You don't believe me?
你让我相信你
Do you really expect me to?
你做出了选择
You made your choice.
你们两个没事吧
Everything okay over here?
没事
Yeah.
我们没事了
Yeah, we're done.
想得美
Nice try.
你以前爱过她 对吧
You were in love with her, weren't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
万事要小心
Just be careful.
你的一大弱点
You sort of have this problem
就是放不下其他人
where you can't walk away from people.
即使应该放下
Even when you should.
你救不了所有人 托马斯
You can't save everyone, Thomas.
总得试试
I can try.
别停下
Don't stop.
快 快
Go, go, go.
等等 等等
Hold on. Hold on.
这个我能搞定
I can get in here.
待着别动 对讲机给我
Stay there. Throw me the walkie.
煎锅 我们进来了 你那边呢
Frypan, we're in. How you doing?
好 快了 我也快到了
Yeah, I'm getting there.
代我向米诺问好
Tell Minho "Hi, " for me.
坚持住 伙计
Hang in there, buddy.
这就行了
This'll work.
布伦达 你那边怎样
Brenda, what's your status?
不怎么样 我在想办法
Status is, I'm working on it.
收到 确保你那边没问题
Copy. Just make sure you're ready on your end.
别担心 我一定会按时到的
Don't worry. You know I'm gonna be there.
可以了 我们走
All right, let's go.
收到信号了
We got a signal.
盖里成功了
Gally did it.
黑进去了
We're in.
很好
Good.
放开手脚干
Give me everything.
彻底控制那里
I want full control.
怪了 系统出故障了
That's funny. System's glitching.
我出去看看
I'll go check it out.
回来 回来 快点
Get back, get back! Move!
走吧 我们快走
Come on, let's go.
快
Move
看着 你们没事了 来吧
It's okay. You guys are okay. Come on.
来吧 我们走 纽特
Come on, let's go. Newt,
去看看另一间牢房
check the other cell.
来吧 没事了 快走
Come on, you guys are okay. Come on.
保险库 怎么进去
The vault. How do I get in?
门都没有
You can't.
大家快点 快走
Come on, guys. Come on.
各位
Guys,
可能得费点工夫
this might take some time.
见鬼
Shit.
他不在这
He's not here.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
真的不能等到明早吗
This really couldn't wait till morning?
你知道他会没命的 对吗
You realize this could kill him, right?
一次注射这么大的剂量
Taking this much, all at once.
一次搞定
I have my orders.
詹森有命令
Janson wants it all.
（囚犯转押令）
米诺被人送到医疗部去了
Somebody's moved him up to the medical wing.
托马斯 医疗部在大楼另一边
Thomas, that's on the other side of the building.
那好 带我去找他 就现在
Okay, take me to him. Right now.
我要跟你一起去
All right. I'm coming with you.
纽特 你不能去
Newt, no, you're not.
听着 你留在这 等盖里拿血清过来
You have to stay here, wait with Gally for the serum.
可你不能一个人去
You can't do this on your own.
米诺不就是个例子吗
Minho comes first, remember?
快走吧 别浪费时间了
Just go. We're wasting time.
我去拿血清 咱们外面会合
I'll get the serum. We'll meet you out back.
那就这样 咱们走 走吧
Okay, fine. Let's go. Come on.
菜鸟
Hey, Greenie.
祝你好运
Good luck.
不要停
Keep moving.
拜托 快点
Come on, come on.
等等
Hold it.
熬夜工作了吧
You're working late.
特瑞莎 我就喜欢你这一点
See, that's what I like about you, Teresa.
不管情况有多糟糕 你
No matter how bleak things get, you just…
你从不轻易放弃
Well, you never give up.
此刻
Times like this,
你需要一个靠得住的朋友
you need a friend that you can count on.
我会好好考虑的
I'll bear that in mind.
有件事你应该知道
There is one thing you should know.
别说是我说的
One friend to another.
托马斯在这
Thomas is here.
我们的监控在墙外发现他了
A surveillance picked him up outside the walls.
艾娃不想让你知道
Ava didn't want you to know,
但是托马斯很可能会去找你
but there is a chance that he may try to contact you,
要是他找你了
and if he does,
好吧
Well.
我希望你能第一时间通知我
I'd like to think that I'd be your first call.
你会杀了他吗
Are you going to kill him?
如果我说会呢
Would that be a problem?
我到了
This is me.
托马斯 你先听我说
Thomas, you have to listen to me.
拿到血清也救不了纽特
Getting that serum won't save Newt.
只能拖延时间 可是
It might buy him some time, but…
不要听她的
Just ignore her.
她这是要给你洗脑
She's trying to get inside your head.
听我说 托马斯 你知道外面的情况
Thomas, listen. You know what's going on out there.
人类要完了 世界也要完了
People are dying. The world is dying.
可你血液的情况我还是搞不明白
There's something about your blood I don't understand.
开门
Open it.
你就让我做几个测试吧
If you let me run some tests…
我发誓我会保护你的
I promise I can protect you.
是吗 像保护米诺那样
Yeah? Like you protected Minho?
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
你们还要牺牲多少人
How many people is it gonna take?
有多少人要被你们抓捕
How many more people do they have to round up,
折磨 杀害
torture, kill?
什么时候才有个完
Huh? When the hell does it stop?
等找到解药就都结束了
It stops when we find a cure.
根本就没有什么解药
There is no goddamn cure!
别白费口舌了 特瑞莎
Don't waste your breath, Teresa.
他早就做出选择了
He made his choice long ago.
把枪放下
Drop it, kid!
退后 叫他们退后
Back up. Tell them to back off.
叫他们退后
Tell them to back off!
托马斯 别这样
Hey, Thomas, come on.
是我
It's me.
我比任何人都了解你
I've known you longer than you can remember.
你绝对不会开枪的
You're not gonna shoot her.
你以为我不敢
You don't think so?
那好
Okay.
开枪啊
Go on then.
打死她
Shoot her.
证明我说错了
Prove me wrong.
打死她
Shoot her.
闪开 闪开
Clear! Clear!
快 快
Move! Move!
给我个合理的解释
Your story better be good.
我这可是在帮你
I just did you a favor.
门都锁上了 他们出不去
Doors are sealed. They can't get out.
詹森 我要抓活的
Janson, I need them alive.
- 跟上 跟我来 - 是 大家跟上
- Come on. Come on! - All right, let's move!
明白 启动三级警报
Yes, sir! Level three, now!
行了 我们得走了 快
Okay. We need to get outta here now.
你们跟紧我 别走散了
You stay close to me. Stick together.
小子 这个一定要保管好 你明白吗
You, you guard this with your life. You understand?
好了
All right.
我们走
Let's go.
封锁整栋大楼 派人来20楼支援
Lock down the building. Send everyone up to 20.
找人关掉那该死的警报器
And someone shut off those goddamn sirens!
是 头儿
Yes, sir.
快 快
Move! Move!
弯腰走 弯腰走
Stay low! Stay low!
快 快 快
Go! Go! Go!
快 弯腰走
Go! Stay low! Stay low!
布伦达 你在哪儿 我们到了
Brenda, where are you? We're here.
上车 我们走 快点
Come on, let's go.
好了 上车 快点
All right. Let's go, let's go. Quickly, quickly.
排好队一个一个上 快点
Front and back, front and back. Let's go.
等等 托马斯在哪儿
Wait, where's Thomas?
他没跟你会合吗
I was hoping he was with you.
快
Come on.
等等 你在这陪着他们
Wait! Wait! Stay here with the kids.
先在这等着
Wait here…
我去找他
I'll find him.
等我们回来 好吗
Just wait for us, okay?
我们哪儿都不会去
We're not going anywhere.
怎么样
Anything?
没发现他们 头儿
No sign of them yet, sir.
对 呃 一定还在这
Yeah, well, they're here somewhere.
他们跑不了 给我搜
They can't get out. Find them.
你们两个 那边
You two, that way.
其他人都跟我来 行动
The rest of you, follow me. Let's go.
- 明白 - 收到
- Yes, sir! - Affirmative.
执行第22号指令
Code 22 in progress.
请16区所有人员到指定位置集合
All R-16 personnel, report to their assigned stations.
趴下 趴下
Get down. Get down.
快快快
Move! Move! Move!
别说话
Stay quiet.
抱歉 托马斯
Sorry, Thomas.
那辆车上面有人
Hey, someone's got the bus.
坐稳了
Hold on!
- 小心 - 停车
- Watch it! - Stop!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
坐稳
It's all right!
装弹 装弹
Load up! Load up!
快点 快
Let's go! Move it!
快 快
Move! Move!
请16区所有人员到指定位置集合
All R-16 personnel, report to their assigned stations.
托马斯 当心
Thomas! No!
米诺 米诺
Minho? Minho!
- 见鬼 - 别动
- Oh, shit! - Freeze!
米诺
Minho!
米诺 你在哪儿
Minho, where are you?
米诺
Minho!
医生 他醒过来了
Doctor, he's coming out of it.
再给我一针镇定剂
Get me another sedative.
该死
Shit!
这边 他们在这
Over here! There they are!
我去拦住他
I'll cut him off!
纽特 趴下
Newt, get down! t
该死 快没子弹了
Shit! I'm almost out.
快退后
Get back.
漂亮 快走
Nice. All right.
咱们走 快
Let's go! Go!
你们俩别动
You two, freeze!
都给我趴在地上
Get down on the ground. Now!
我叫你们趴
I said get your…
米诺
Minho.
这是真的吗
Is this real?
找到了 找到了 这边
I got him! I got him! Over here.
快点
Come on!
你们三个 站住
You three! Stop!
快跑
Come on.
这边 进去
In here, in here.
纽特 快来
Newt, come on.
找人给我把门弄开
Somebody get this door open.
是 头儿
Yes, sir!
该死
Oh, shit.
有办法吗
Any ideas?
有了
Maybe.
行了 肯定管用
Okay, it's doable.
只不过得先来个助跑
Just need a little running start.
就快弄开了
Almost through.
真要这么干吗
You sure about this?
我也不想
Not really.
好歹鼓个劲啊
Nice pep talk.
对 你可真会打气
Yeah, we're all bloody inspired.
- 进去 进去 - 该死
- Move it! Move it! - Shit.
快 快
Go! Go!
托马斯
Thomas!
天哪
Oh, shit!
- 米诺 你没事吧 - 没事
- Minho, you okay? - Yeah.
你们三个都别动
You three, don't move.
开什么玩笑
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
慢慢靠近
Take it easy.
不要轻举妄动
Don't even think about it.
跪到地上 双手举起来
Get on your knees with your hands in the air.
盖里
Gally?
米诺
Minho.
你们真是疯了
You guys are nuts.
待会跟你解释
I'll explain later.
派人抓他们
Drop the net.
宣布开始戒严 禁止所有人进出
Declare martial law. No one leaves until they're found.
安排好了 巡逻队发现一辆公交车
It's done, sir. We already have eyes on the bus.
正在追捕
Our patrols are in pursuit.
公交车？
What bus?
该死 坐稳了
Shit! Hold on!
见鬼
Shit!
全都给我下车
Get out of the vehicle.
都别动
Don't move.
你们都很棒
You're doing great.
现在从那里走过来
Now step away from the vehicle.
我让你从那里走过来
I said step away from the vehicle!
把手举起来
Put your hands in the air.
快把枪放下
Drop the weapon!
好戏开场
Here we go.
给我冲 给我冲
Push in! Push in! Go! Go!
- 别让那辆车跑了 - 快 快
- That bus does not leave! - Move! Move in!
快点 找个东西抓紧
Come on, hold on to something!
我们走了
Here we go.
包围起来 快 快 不要开火
Circle up! Go! Go! Hold fire!
都抓紧了
Brace yourself.
抱歉
Sorry.
真该死
Shit.
找个东西抓紧
Hold on to something!
好了 大家下车
Okay. Everybody off.
安静点
Shut up.
他们还没逃出去
They're not out yet.
我看他们肯定气疯了
Well, they're definitely pissed.
离隧道有多远
How far are the tunnels?
隔着12个街区吧
Uh, maybe 12 blocks from here.
我们能赶到
We can make it.
纽特 你怎么样
Newt, how are you feeling?
不怎么样
Terrible.
见到你真好
It's good to see you though.
嘿
Hey.
他这种情况多久了
How long has he been like this?
他会没事的 我们得去找布伦达
He'll be okay. We just gotta get to Brenda.
她有血清
She's got the serum.
行了 我们走
Come on, let's go.
嘿 纽特
Hey, Newt.
坚持住 我们扶着你 快走吧
Come on, bud. We gotta get you up. Let's go.
- 不要紧吧 - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
你为什么要帮我们 盖里
Why you helping us, Gally?
我在你胸口开了个洞
I put a spear through your chest.
对
Yeah.
不过人无完人
Nobody's perfect, man.
劳伦斯
Lawrence!
等等 孩子们 先等等
Wait, guys. Wait, wait, wait.
他们人呢
Where is everyone?
先在这等等
Wait here, guys. Wait.
托马斯
Thomas!
嘿
Hey!
劳伦斯
Lawrence!
什么都没了
Everything's gone.
大家不用怕
Don't be scared.
我是长得不好看
I may not be pretty,
可我们的敌人更恶心
but we all know who the enemies are,
躲在墙后的胆小鬼
cowering behind those walls!
像我们这样的人
They have a name
他们还给起了个名字
for people like us in there.
他们叫我们狂客
They call us Cranks!
我说他们才是怪物
But I say that they are the monsters.
这场战争是他们发动的
They're the ones who started this war,
不过今晚
but tonight,
我们来终结它
we will finish it.
跟随我
Follow me.
跟随我 他们既然想遗忘我们
Follow me, and we will show them the faces of the people
那我们就让他们看看我们这张脸
that they have chosen to forget!
跟着我夺取这个城市
Follow me and this city is yours!
准备出发
Let's move it!
我们走
Let's go!
监控部 看到了吗
Control, you seeing this?
请求指示
Please advise.
我的天
Holy shit.
一号 二号炮塔准备开火
Get turrets one and two ready to fire.
炮塔没有反应 我控制不了
Guns aren't responding. I'm locked out.
快过来 向前移动
All right. Move forward.
开火 开火
Open fire! Open fire!
我们应该摧毁实验部
We're supposed to take down WICKED,
而不是全城
not the whole damn city.
盖里 走吧
Gally, come on.
现在发布强制撤离令
This is a mandatory evacuation.
最后一班车将在38分钟后出发
The last transport leaves in 38 minutes.
请前往屋顶集合
Please proceed to the roof.
重复一遍 现在发布强制撤离令
I repeat, this is a mandatory evacuation.
特瑞莎 你还留在这干什么 我们得走了
Teresa, what are you still doing here? We have to leave.
不 我还不能走 我要等托马斯
No, I can't leave. Not without Thomas.
来不及了 他己经走了
It's too late for that. He's gone.
不 你还不明白
No. You don't understand.
我需要他的血
I need more.
快过来看
Come. Look.
它不只减缓了病毒扩散
It's not just slowing the virus down.
还在杀死病毒
It's destroying it.
我们要找到托马斯
We need to find Thomas.
隧道就在前面了
Tunnels are right up ahead.
见鬼
Shit!
躲起来 躲起来
Hey! Stay low! Stay low!
见鬼
Shit!
准备好
Get ready!
好了 往前冲 往前冲
All right, move up! Move up!
一线部队撤离
Frontline down!
真见鬼
Damn it!
他们在等什么
What are they waiting for?
躲起来 趴下
Get down, get down!
趴下 趴下
Stay down! Stay down!
该死 我们快走 快走
We gotta go. We gotta go.
快点 我们走 赶快走
Come on. Let's move, let's move.
听到没有 听到没有
Get him in, get him in.
布伦达 布伦达听到了吗
Brenda, are you there?
听到了 托马斯
Thomas, I'm here.
见鬼 没事吧
Shit! You okay?
我们可能活不了了
We're not gonna make it.
你这话是什么意思
Wait, what are you talking about?
别让他们跑了
Don't let them get away!
带其他人走
Just take the others.
趁还不晚把大家救出去
Get everybody out while you still can.
不行
No.
布伦达
Brenda.
我不会扔下你们
I'm not leaving you.
懂吗
Okay?
想都别想
So forget it.
即使应该扔下
Even though you should?
托马斯 不用担心
Thomas, don't worry.
我过去找你
I'm coming to you.
你刚才说什么
What are you talking about?
救兵来了
Our ride's here!
来隧道附近找我们
Just look for us near the tunnels.
好了 咱们走 孩子们 快 救兵到了
Let's go, guys! Move! Our ride's here!
- 当心 - 跟上 跟上
- Careful. - Move! Move!
当心脚下 好吗
Watch your step. Okay?
文斯
Vince?
嘿 招呼都不会打了吗
Hey, it's good to see you, too.
是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我让他搭了便车
I picked up a stray.
咱们先离开这里
Let's get out of here, all right?
还不能走
We're not done yet.
托马斯还在里面呢
Thomas is still inside.
那咱们去救他啊
Well, let's go get him then.
没问题
Hell yeah.
- 大家快上来 - 快上 快上
- On board. Everybody. - Let's go! Step up! Step up!
我们要走了 我们要走了
We gotta move, we gotta move.
- 行了 纽特 - 我们快到了
- All right. Newt, - We're almost there.
你们别管我了
Just leave me.
退后 退后
Back! Back!
我们上 冲啊
Let's go! Let's go!
杀了他们
Take 'em out!
- 好了 他们来了 - 对
- Okay, that's them. - Yeah.
他们来了 我们走
It's them. We gotta go.
- 快走 - 你们别管我了
- We gotta go. - Go without me, man.
你只要
You should just…
米诺
Minho.
你先跑过去 拿到血清
You gotta run ahead, grab the serum,
然后就尽快赶回来
and get back to us as soon as you can.
米诺 去吧
Minho, go.
听他的 我掩护你
He's right. I can cover.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢你 米诺
Thank you, Minho.
你要挺住
Hey, you just hang on.
听见了吗
You hear me?
走 米诺 快走
Go, Minho, go!
好了 他们过去了
Okay, they're through.
纽特 纽特
Newt? Newt?
嘿 嘿 纽特 嘿
Hey! Hey! Newt! Hey!
我们要搏一搏 好吗
We're gonna try this. Okay?
现在就走 快 我来扶你 快点
We gotta move, now. Let's get you up, come on.
- 走吧 快点 - 不 不 托马斯
- Let's go, come on. - No. No, Thomas.
等等 必须得走了
No, Newt. Later. Later. Really gotta go.
- 快点 - 给 你带上这个
- Come on. - Look, you gotta take this.
- 我先扶你起来 - 你带上这个
- We gotta get you up, now. - No, just take it!
拜托
Please.
拜托 求你了 拜托
Please, Tommy. Please.
好的
All right.
好了 我要你带东西一起跟我走
All right. I need you to give me everything you got.
你我 马上走 准备好
You and me, right now. Let's go. You ready?
撑住 好了吗 我们走
Come on, ready? Here we go.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
大家别出来 别出来
Get back, guys, get back!
天啊
Oh, man.
没事的 我们马上离开这
It's okay, guys. We're getting out of here soon.
不能留在这里了 布伦达
We can't stay here, Bren.
别着急 他们会来的
Don't worry. They'll be here.
快 快
Come on. Come on.
就快到了 纽特 跟我来 挺住
We're almost there, Newt. Stay with me, come on.
纽特 不 不 嘿
Newt, no, no. Hey!
撑住
Come on.
托马斯
Thomas?
你听到了吗
Can you hear me?
现在请你听我说
I need you to listen to me.
我知道你没理由相信我
I know you have no reason to trust me,
可我需要你回来
but I need you to come back.
托马斯 你可以救纽特的命
Thomas, you can save Newt.
他还有机会活命
There's still time for him.
布伦达没有病发是有原因的
There's a reason Brenda isn't sick anymore.
是因为你的血
It's your blood.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
她没病发
She isn't sick,
是因为你治好了她
because you cured her.
你能救的不止她一个
She doesn't have to be the only one.
你只需要回来就好
All you have to do is come back.
我们一起结束这一切
And this will all finally be over.
求你了
Please.
回我这边来
Just come back to me.
我知道你是个好人
I know you'll do the right…
纽特
Newt?
纽特 纽特 是我 是我
Newt? Newt, it's me. It's me!
布伦达
Brenda!
血清在哪儿
Where's the serum?
托马斯 杀了我
Tommy, kill me!
纽特 我在这
Newt, I'm here.
纽特 别这样
Newt, please!
拜托
Please!
对不起 真的对不起 托马斯
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, Tommy.
没关系 没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
不
No!
布伦达
Brenda!
托马斯
Thomas!
趴下 快趴下
Stay down, stay down!
纽特
Newt.
托马斯
Tommy.
不 不
No, no.
No, no, no.
纽特
Newt?
是真的吗
Is it true?
纽特
Newt.
我能救他的吗
Could I have saved him?
你能救我们所有人
You can save us all.
没事了
It's okay.
放其他人走好吗
Just leave the others alone.
我答应你
I promise.
我会
I will…
托马斯
Oh, Thomas.
你应该逃跑的
You should have run.
托马斯
Thomas.
听到了吗
Can you hear me?
知道这是什么地方吗 托马斯
Do you know what this place is, Thomas?
这是救生船
It's a lifeboat.
整个世界就要毁灭了
And the whole world might be sinking,
可并不意味着我们也要陪葬
but doesn't mean that we have to go down with it.
还要多久
How much longer?
差不多了
It's almost done.
为什么不杀了我
Why don't you just kill me?
杀了你
Kill you?
我才不舍得杀你呢
No, we don't wanna do that.
我们会好好照顾你的
We're gonna take special care of you.
留下你的小命
We'll keep you alive.
只不过
Just.
作为报答
And in return,
你得救我们其他人的命
you will give life to the rest of us.
也就是我们选中的人
The ones we choose to save, anyway.
你也知道我们救不了所有人
Of course, there's not gonna be enough for everyone.
做这样的选择实在太难了
Hard choices are gonna have to be made.
耀斑病毒早晚有一天会彻底消失
In time, the Flare virus will burn itself out.
可唯一的问题是
The only question is,
最终都有哪些人能够活下来
who will be the ones left standing?
多亏了你 还有这个
And thanks to you, to this,
我们终于可以选择
we finally get to choose.
自己亲手创造一个未来
A future of our own making.
祝你健康
To your health.
好了 我们赶快走
Okay, let's get out of here.
拜托
Come on.
不
No!
你给我回来
Get back here.
回来
Get back!
不
No!
把它给我
Give it to me.
Give it to me!
特瑞莎
Teresa!
来啊
Come on.
好了
Okay.
玩够了
That's enough.
- 武器准备 - 听我命令
- Weapons ready! - On my command.
装弹
Charge it!
准备
Ready.
开火
Fire!
特瑞莎
Teresa!
我们得逃出去
We need to get out of here.
怎么了
What's wrong?
托马斯
Thomas?
Thomas!
- 没事 我们要 - 见鬼
- Okay. Okay, we need to… - Oh, shit…
拜托 在哪里 这里
Find something. Here. Here!
这样 用手压住伤口 按住
Just put pressure on it. Hold it.
你快走吧
You gotta go.
不
No.
要走一起走
Not without you.
特瑞莎 你真把我给骗了
I admit, Teresa, you had me fooled.
我以为我们是朋友
I thought we were friends.
也许背叛身边最亲近的人
Maybe it's just in your nature to betray
就是你这个人的本性
the people closest to you.
出来吧
Come on.
不要拖延时间了
Let's not prolong this.
你我都知道你们出不去了
We both know there's no way outta here.
现在出来我还能给你们一个痛快
Let's not make this any more painful than it needs to be.
托马斯
Thomas.
特瑞莎
Teresa.
不 不
No. No.
你好像拿了我的东西
I think you have something of mine.
不是那个
Not that.
他在哪里
Where is he?
拿这个走吧
Just take it.
放过他吧
Leave him alone.
你们俩怎么回事
What is it with you two?
你以为他很特别吗
You think he's so special?
他就是只小白鼠 生来就能免疫病毒
He's a lab rat. He was born with a gift.
不必抗争 不必付出努力
He never had to fight for it, he never earned it.
他根本就不配
He doesn't deserve it.
也许吧
Maybe.
但那是天意
But it's his.
你怎么想 托马斯
What about you, Thomas?
想说点什么吗
What do you have to say?
你的手上沾的血还不够多吗
Don't you have enough blood on your hands already?
你不忍心向她开枪
You might not have been able to shoot her.
但我忍心
But I can.
行啊 好
Okay. Fine.
随你的便吧
Have it your way.
詹森
Janson.
你失手了 小畜生
Missed, you little shit.
是吗
Did I?
该死
Oh, shit.
快走 我们赶快走
Come on. We need to go.
走这边 这里
This way. Here.
我们走
Come on.
撑住
对不起 我
I'm sorry.
尽力了
I tried.
我 我知道
I know.
我好像看到他了
I think I got him.
对 就是他 我去开门
Yeah, that's him. I'll get the hatch.
好了 找到他了 找到他了
All right, I got him, I got him.
快点
Come on.
不
No!
我们不能再靠近了
I can't get any closer.
托马斯
Thomas!
快
Now!
快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
- 快点 - 快点 托马斯
- Come on! - Come on, Thomas!
把手给我
Give me your hand!
再近一点
Get closer!
跳啊
Jump!
低点
Lower!
不
No!
你们再靠近点
You gotta get closer.
站起来
Come on!
好
Yeah!
- 快点 过来 撑住 - 近点
- Come on, reach! Come on! - Reach!
- 拉他上来 - 用力
- Pull him up! - Pull!
上来 快啊
Come on! Come on!
特瑞莎
Teresa!
不
No!
我们历经了千辛万苦
We have come a long way together.
无数人牺牲了生命
So many have sacrificed so much
才最终建立了这个家园
to make this place possible.
有我们的朋友
Your friends
我们的家人
and your family.
这一杯敬死去的同伴
So here's to the ones who couldn't be here.
敬我们失去的朋友
Here's to the friends we lost.
这里是你的家 是每个人的家
This place is for you. It's for all of us.
但这个
But this,
这个献给他们
this is for them.
好好利用时间 以自己的方式
So, in your own time, in your own way,
找到平静吧
come make your peace.
欢迎来到避风港
And welcome to the Safe Haven.
想吃东西吗
You all want some food?
这以后就是我们的家了
This is gonna be a good home for us.
是啊
Yeah.
你晕倒的时候还握着这个
You had this on you while you were passed out.
我保管得还不错吧
Figured I'd keep it safe for ya.
谢谢 米诺
Thanks, Minho.
待会见
See you out there.
See ya.
亲爱的托马斯
Dear Thomas…
这是我有记忆以来写的第一封信
This is the first letter I can remember writing.
当然我不记得进迷宫前写过没有
Obviously, I don't know if I wrote any before the maze.
但即使这不是我的第一封信 也应该是最后一封
But even if it's not my first, it's likely to be my last.
我想让你知道 我不害怕
I want you to know that I'm not scared.
至少我怕的不是死亡 而是遗忘
Well, not of dying, anyway. It's more forgetting.
我怕病毒夺走我的记忆
It's losing myself to this virus.
这才是我最害怕的
That's what scares me.
所以我每晚都大声念出他们的名字
So every night I've been saying their names out loud.
艾尔比
Alby…
温斯顿 查克
Winston, Chuck.
我像做祈祷一样一遍又一遍地重复着
And I just repeat them over and over, like a prayer,
记忆就像潮水般涌来
and it all comes flooding back.
都是些小事 比如夕阳沉下高墙前
Just the little things, like the way the sun used to hit the Glade
余晖挂在林间空地的那一刹那
at that perfect moment right before it slipped beneath the walls.
我还想起了煎锅炖的菜
And I remember the taste of Frypan's stew.
想不到我会这么怀念那东西
I never thought I'd miss that stuff so much.
我也记得你
And I remember you.
记得你被装进笼子送进来
I remember the first time you came up in the Box.
那时你惊慌失措
Just a scared little Greenie
连名字都不记得
who couldn't even remember his own name.
但从你冲进迷宫的那一刻起
But from that moment you ran into the maze,
我就知道我会追随你
I knew I would follow you anywhere.
我做到了
And I have.
我们都做到了
We all have.
如果一切能够重新来过
If I could do it all over again, I would
我还会做出同样的选择
and I wouldn't change a thing.
而且我也希望
And my hope for you
当你多年后回首往事时
is that when you're looking back years from now,
也会说出同样的话
you'll be able to say the same.
未来在你手中 托马斯
The future's in your hands now, Tommy.
你一定能找到正确的道路
And I know you'll find a way to do what's right.
你有这个能力
You always have.
帮我照顾好大家
Take care of everyone for me.
也照顾好你自己
And take care of yourself.
你值得拥有幸福
You deserve to be happy.
谢谢你做我的朋友
Thank you for being my friend.
再见了 兄弟
Goodbye, mate.
纽特
Newt.